

Curriculum Vitae for Jakob Emil Schreiner

Personal information

Address: Presidentgata 3a E-mail: jakob@xal.no

0474 Oslo Phone: +47 991 52 009

Born: 26.02.1992 Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

I submitted my master's degree in Computational Science and Engineering at the University of Oslo in 2016. My educational background is in mathematics and computational science applied on mechanical problems using numerical methods. This has fuelled my interest for science and technology. I have mainly used Python and have substantial experience using numerical libraries such as Numpy/Scipy and FEniCS. I am also familiar with C/C++ and Java. My experience include teaching introductory Python at the University of Oslo, mostly in one-to-one settings.

Before joining Expert Analytics I was engaged as a Research Engineer at Simula Research Laboratory. In my thesis I simulated the cerebrospinal fluid flow in patient specific geometries. I solved partial differential equations with the finite element method using supercomputers, both in my master's thesis and during my work at Simula. Through my education and work I have gained significant experience with numerical simulations and mathematical modelling, as well as problem solving in general.

Technical skills

Frameworks MPI, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, FEniCS, Pybind, Tensorflow, scikit-

learn, keras

Languages Python, Java, C/C++, Bash

Tools Git, Vim editor, Linux, Paraview, LATEX

Education

Ph.D in mathematics at Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo. The project is a collaboration between Expert Analytics, Simula Research Laboratory, Haukeland Universitetssykehus and the University of Oslo. Supervisors: Professor Kent-Andre Mardal, Ph.D Ola Skavhaug, Ph.d, MD Leif Oltadal, Professor Aslak Tveito
2014 – 2016 M.Sc in Computational Science and Engineering at the University of Oslo. My thesis was titled Computational Fluid Mechanics Modelling of Cerebrospinal Fluid Flow in Patient Specific Geometries. Supervisors: Professor Kent Andre Mardal, Postdoctoral Fellow Erika Kristina Lindström
2011 – 2014 B.Sc degree in applied mathematics at the University of Oslo.

Professional experience

2013 – 2015 Teacher's assistant at the University of Oslo in the introductory course to Python for scientific applications.

 I was responsible for a weekly programming lab as well as student evaluation.

2016 – 2017 Research Engineer at Simula Research Laboratory.

 I developed code for the simulation of the fluid structure interaction between the blood flow in the Ophthalmic artery and arterial wall as part of the iBrainSafeCLOUD project.

2017 – IT Consultant at Expert Analytics AS.

Languages

English Proficient for professional work

Norwegian Mother tongue

Personal skills

Problem I can grasp new ideas and technologies relatively easily, and enjoy Solving using mathematics to get solve real world problems in a broad range

of fields.

Technology I am always eager to learn anything new in science and technology.

Some interests and hobbies

Personal History, Economics, Bicycling

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Computational Fluid Dynamics Modelling of Cerebrospinal Fluid Flow

in Patient Specific Geometries.

Role Researcher and developer

Staffing 1 researcher

Description In my master's thesis I simulated the cerebrospinal fluid flow in patient

specific geometries, with the goal of reproducing the measured velocity

and pressure.

Tools Python, FEniCS, vmtk and ParaView

Activity Finite Element software for the fluid structure interaction in the Opht-

halmic artery.

Role Researcher and developer

Staffing 2 researchers

Description During the fall of 2016 I worked at the iBrainSafeCloud project at Si-

mula Research Laboratory as a research engineer. The work involved writing a fully decoupled fluid structure interaction solver. Furthermore, we made a web user interface enabling non-expert users to perform simulations on a supercomputer. It was implemented using the Python

interface of FEniCS.

Tools Python, FEniCS and Git

Activity Finite element and mesh generation software for modelling of elect-

roconvulsive therapy.

Role Researcher and developer

Staffing 1 researcher

Description During a six week project I created a simulator for the electrical cur-

rents in the human brain intended for simulations of electroconvulsive therapy. The software includes geometrical modelling and mesh generation for the skull and brain, as well as an efficient numerical solver using the finite element method. The project was in cooperation with

Simula Research Laboratory.

Tools Python, FEniCS and Git

Activity Machine learning for Oncolmmunity

Role Consultant Staffing 5 defelopers

Description Oncolmmunity develop bioinformatics software that has the ability

to empower precision cancer immunotherapy, and thus improves the outlook for patients with late-stage disease. My role is to develop machine-learning methods applied to genomic data for tumor immune profiling. The goal is to select optimal patients to be assigned to cancer

immunotherapy clinical trials.

Tools Python, Keras